"CASTLE" 지난 이야기...
Previously on "Castle"...
누가 제 어머니를 죽였죠?
Who killed my mother?
난 널 알기 때문에 알려줄수없어, 케이트
No, Kate. I give you a name, I know you.
You'll run straight at him.
내가 이름을 알려주면
넌 바로 놈을 찾아갈 거잖아
I might as well shoot you where you stand.
차라리 지금 이 자리에서
자넬 쏘겠어
They are coming to kill you,
and I'm not gonna let 'em.
그들은 지금 자넬 죽이러 오고있어
그리고 난 그렇게 두진 않겠어
내가 끝을 맺을 거야
I'm gonna end this.
이 직계 가족
이외의 사람은
No one outside of this immediate family
이 일에 대해
알아서는 안 돼
ever needs to know about this.
세상이 그렇게 아는 한,
As far as the world is concerned,
로이 몽고메리는 영웅으로서 죽은 거야
Roy Montgomery died a hero.
케이트!
Kate!
이 일은 끝났어야 했어요
It was supposed to be over.
몽고메리가 그녈위해
자신을 희생했으닌까요
Montgomery sacrificed
himself to keep her safe.
이 일은 자네가 생각하는것보다
훨씬 큰 사건이라네
This is so much bigger than you realize.
-Hello
-캐슬씨,
Hello.
Mr. Castle,
저는 롱고메리의 친구 입니다
I'm a friend of Roy Montgomery's.
할 이야기가 있습니다
We need to talk.
그가 말하길
베켓이 그녀의 어머니 사건근처에 가지않는다면
He says she's safe now on one condition.
지금 현재로는 안전하다 했어요
She can't go near her mother's case.
그녀는 제 의견을 따라줄꺼에요
제가 그녀의 마음을 움직이게할거에요
She'll listen to me. I can steer her away.
No! Ah!
베켓!
Beckett!
캐슬!
Castle!
베켓!
Beckett!
캐슬, 여기에요!
Castle, I'm here!
베켓, 버티고 있어요!
Beckett, hang on!
내가 지금까지 꿈을꾼것중
가장 지루한 꿈이거나
Either this is the most
boring dream I've ever had
혹은 너가 자지 못하는 꿈이거나
or you can't sleep either.
이건 꿈이아니에요
꿈보단 악몽(nightmare)에 가깝죠
It's not a dream. More like a nightmare.
이게 너의 졸업식 대표 연설문이니?
Is this about your valedictorian speech?
이것은 제가 무엇인가 중요한것을,
It's my chance to say something important,
뭔가 가치있는걸 이야기할
기회에요
something worthy.
전 이 기회를 날리고 싶지않지만,
왠지 내가 할말이 없는것 처럼 느껴져요
I don't want to blow it, but I
feel like I have nothing to say.
너의 뜻은 인류의 위대한 문자와
You mean nothing compared to
윈스턴 처칠의 harrows 에게의 연설이나
(harrows의 정확한 뜻을 모르겠습니다ㅠ)
the great sacred texts of mankind
아니면, 스티브 잡스의
스탠포드에서의 강의로는
or Winston Churchill's speech to harrows,
비교할수 없다는거니?
or Steve Jobs' address to Stanford?
저기,
여러 연설문들을 비교해서
You know, maybe you
should pick some speeches
너가 몇가지를 고르는건 어떨까?
st a little less daunting
to compare yours to,
마치, 음, "Say Anything" 혹은 "Twilight."처럼
like, um, "Say Anything" or "Twilight."
이렇게까지 어려워야할 필요는 없어요
It's not supposed to be this hard.
You know, 가끔 인생에서
가장 가치있는 일들은
You know, the most
worthwhile things in life
가장 어려운 일들이란다
are often the most difficult.
에를 들어....
For example--
와우, 이거 진짜 스마트 폰이네
Wow. That really is a smart phone.
당연히 당신은 이해를 못하겠죠
Of course you don't understand
왜 알렉시스가
졸업 연설문을 심각하게 받아들이는지를
why she's taking her graduation
speech so seriously.
당신은 마치 가운 밑에
속옷 빼고 아무것도 입지 않은
You were probably the guy who
had nothing on but boxers
사람 같아요(boxers:남성용팬티)
(라고 말하는것 같습니다;;)
underneath his gown.
모욕적이네요
That is so insulting.
그렇게 알고싶다면 나는 밑에를 벗겠어요
If you must know, I was naked underneath.
아, 미안해요 그 말 취소할께요
Oh, I'm sorry. I stand corrected.
그래서 졸업식때 어떻게 할껀가요?
So how is the father of
the graduate taking it?
전 이미 제 슬픔을 가라앉히는
계획을 가지고 있어요
I already have a plan to drown my sorrows.
졸업식 후, 어머니는
함튼으로 갈 것이고,
After the ceremony, my mother
goes off to the Hamptons,
알렉시스는 밤새도록 그녀의 일을 할것이고
Alexis will be doing her all-nighter.
전 아마도
"The Killer" 와 "Hard Boiled"
I will be distracting myself
with a double feature
이 두가지로
제 마음을 다스리겠죠
of "The Killer" and "Hard Boiled."
Wow. That is a double feature
Wow. That is a double feature.
존 우 좋아해요?
You like John Woo?
The bloodier the better
The bloodier the better.
당신은 아마... 저와있기싫죠, 그렇죠?
You wouldn't want to... join me, would you?
사실, 좋아요
Actually, I'd love to.
캐슬, 올 거에요?
You coming, Castle?
Yeah. Please
Yeah. Please.
Hey.
그래서?
So?
히스패닉 20대 후반 남성이 발견되었고
(히스패닉:스페인과 관련 있거나 스페인어를 사용하는사람)
So we've got a Hispanic male, late 20s.
택시기사가 한시간전 시체를 발견하고
Cabbie spotted the body about an hour ago
신고를 했어요
and called it in.
신원은 알아냈어?
We got an I.D.?
아뇨, 주머니를 확인해보았는데
Nah. We checked his pockets.
안에 전화기나 키 혹은 지갑도 없었어요
There's no phone, keys, or wallet.
그리고 지금 지문 조회하고 있어요
And we're checking prints right now.
핏자국을 보면
그가 골목을 들어가기전
From the blood trail, it
looks like he was shot
총에 맞은 것 같아요
before he entered the alley.
우선 피해자는 38구경으로
He was hit in the shoulder
어깨에 타박상을 입었어
with what looks like a .357,
하지만 킬샷은
9mm로 정면에서
but the kill shot--
point-blank, execution style,
깨끗하게 전문적으로 정확하게 맞았어
with a 9 millimeter.
두개의 총
범인이 한명 이상일수도 있겠네요
Two guns. Could be more than one shooter.
C.S.U.에서 첫 샷부터
Was C.S.U. able to trace that blood trail
핏자국을 추적할수있어?
from the first shot?
코너쯤에서 부터 시작됐어요
It starts around the corner.
아직까지 특별히 눈에 띄는점은 없지만
There's no visible point of origin,
계속해서 찾아보고 있어요
but the teams are still looking.
여긴 꽤 외진 곳이네
Well, this is a bad neighborhood.
혹시 강도를 만났다가 잘못된 것일까?
Maybe it was a mugging gone wrong?
아마도
Maybe.
여기 어깨의 파진 홈을 보아
These grooves in his shoulder indicate
그가 뭔가 무거운것을 지니고(나르고)
있었던거 같아
that he was carrying
something, and it was heavy.
내생각엔 적어도 30파운드 정도
I'd say at least 30 pounds.
피해자의 손톱 밑에서
피부 조직을 발견했어
I'm even seeing traces of skin
tissue in his fingernail.
내가 DNA 조회를 통해 알아낼수 있지만
I may be able to get D.N.A.,
그러나, 내가 부검실로 돌아가면
더 많은 것을 알아 낼수있을거야
but I'll know a lot more once
I get him back to the morgue.
어, 그의 주머니는 비어있었지만
Uh, his pockets may have been empty,
신발엔 무언가
숨킬려고 했었던거 같은데요
but it looks like he was trying
to hide something in his shoe.
Lock picks?
(자물쇠 이런것을 딸수있는 기구)
이제, 누가 lock picks 를 필요로 한걸까?
Now why would someone
be needing lock picks?
그는 도둑이에요
He's a thief.
올랜도 코스타스
Orlando Costas.
몇번 주거침입죄로 걸렸었지만
의심되는점은 더 있어요
A couple of domestic B&Es, but
suspected of a dozen more.
그는 카제도레스와 일을 실행하는데 사용했어요
He used to run with the Cazadores.
카제도레스?
Cazadores?
그들은 거리에서
절도와 마약 거래를 하는
They're a violent street
gang that deals in drugs,
위험한 갱이에요
arms, and larceny,
그러나 올랜도의 청소년때
전과 기록은 되돌아 왔죠
but all of Orlando's priors are
back when he was a teenager.
몇년동안 그는 체포되지 않았어요
He hasn't been arrested in years.
그는 아마 게임에 다시 돌아왔나 보네요
Maybe he got back in the game.
저도 잘 모르죠
그는 죄를 씻기 위해 멀리갔었네요
I don't know. He went a long
way to clean up his act.
4년동안 군대에서 있었으며
Did four years active in the military,
작년에 명예롭게 퇴직했고
discharged with honors last year.
그는 독일에서 헌병으로 활동했었네요
Spent his rotation as an M.P. in Germany.
헌병이요? 그는 정말
본인의 죄를 씻었네요
Military police? He really
did clean up his act.
그가 정말 바르게 나갔다면
If this guy went straight,
어떻게 그 골목길에서 죽었겠어요?
then how did he end up dead in an alley?
피해자 친척들은 확인해 봤어?
Did you check for next of kin?
친척들 모두 죽었지만
Uh, his folks are dead,
우리는 여자친구인
마리솔 카사네다를 추적할수 있었어요
but we managed to track down a
girlfriend--Marisol Castaneda.
에스파지토가 데리고 오고 있어요
Esposito's bringing her in right now.
제가 아는 전부는,
지난 밤 제가 잠들때까지
All I know is, he was
with me in bed last night
침대에 같이있었던 것 뿐이에요
when I went to sleep.
오늘 아침 일어나보니
I woke up this morning,
그는 이미 제 차를 타고
떠났어요
and both him and my car were gone.
그는 어디로 갔죠?
Where did he go?
전 그가 일을 찾기 위해
I figured he'd gone to the career center
직업 센터에 간 줄 알았어요
to check the job listings.
매일 아침마다 가거든요
He does that every morning.
그는 일을 찾고 있었나요?
He'd been looking for work?
몇 개월 동안요
For months.
올랜도는 나라를 위해 복무했어요
Orlando served his country.
당신이 생각하기에
무언가 의미가 있다고 생각하겠지만
You'd think that means something,
저에겐 시간이 지난수록
but it's been tough,
그것은 굉장히 힘들었어요
especially after my hours got cut.
그래서 그는 재정적으로
어려움을 겪고있나요?
So he was under financial pressure?
그가 예전 습관으로
되돌아갈 가능성이 있나요?
Is it possible that he
went back to old habits?
아니요
No.
마리솔, 우린 그가
카제도레스와 일을 벌린것을 알아요
Look, Marisol, we know that
he ran with the Cazadores.
-당신이 생각하기에
-아니라고 말했잖아요
Do you think that--
I said no.
그는 그 지옥같은 삶으로 부터 도망쳤어요
He went through hell to escape that life.
그래서 그는 입대를 한거에요
It's why he enlisted, to get out,
나를 위해 더 나은 남자가 되기위해...
to be a better man for me...
우리 아들에게 더 좋은 아빠가 되기위해
A better father to our son.
이제 그만 그를 의심하고
So how about you stop trying
to make this his fault
그를 죽인 범인을 찾는건 어떤가요?
and find whoever killed him?
어떤 차를 소유하고 있죠?
What kind of car do you have?
그 골목으로부터 두 블럭 떨어져 있고,
Two blocks away from the alley,
팔 받침대에 피가 묻어있으므로
이 차가 확실하네요
blood smeared on the arm rest--
This is definitely it.
다른 곳에서 총을 맞고
이 곳으로 온 것인가?
He was shot somewhere else
and then he came here?
왜 집으로 안갔을까요?
왜 치료를 하지 않았을까요?
Why not go home? Why not go get patched up?
그는 골목길에서 누군가를 만났어요
He was meeting someone in that alleyway.
전화기네요
Phone.
마지막 전화는 4:47 A.M.,
그가 바로 죽기 전이네요
His last call was 4:47 A.M.,
just before he died.
-그 번호로 전화해봐
-알겠습니다
Run that number.
Right.
베켓, 총이 있어요
Hey, Beckett, gun.
38구경이네요
It's a .38.
최근 발사되었어요
Recently fired.
그럼 이게 총격전에 사용되었겠네
So it was a shootout.
-그래서 그가 어깨에 총상을 입었군요
-그 말은 즉,
That's how he got the shoulder wound.
Which means,
그가 있었던 곳에
다른 시체가 있을수도 있겠네요
wherever he came from, there
might be another body.
전 어디서 왔는지 알것같아요
I know where he was coming from.
어디요?
Where?
그가 마지막으로 있던곳은
299 First Avenue에요
His last entry was 299 First Avenue.
잠깐, 299 First Ave에 뭐가 있었죠?
Wait. What's at 299 First Ave.?
캡틴 몽고메리의 집이요
Captain Montgomery's house.
아무도 다치질 않아 다행이네요
We're just thankful no one was hurt.
나도 그래요
Believe me, so am I.
로이가 죽은 이후로,
Ever since Roy died,
나는 스탠드에있는 그의 38구경을 놓고 자요
I've slept with his .357 in the nightstand.
한 남자 뿐이었나요?
So it was just the one guy?
제가 아는 한으로는요
As far as I know.
그는 캐비넷 파일들을 꺼내고 있었어요
He was taking files out of the cabinet.
그의 가방엔 로이의 낡은 노트북이 있었어요
He had Roy's old laptop in his backpack.
그가 절 본 순간
그는 총을 뽑아 들었고
When he saw me, he pulled his weapon,
신이 도와 난 그를 쐈어요
so God help me, I shot him.
제 생각엔 그의 어깨에 쏜 것 같아요
I think I hit him in his shoulder.
그는 다시 총을 쏘았고
그 뒤 창문으로 도망쳤어요
He fired back, and then he
crashed through the window.
에블린, 이 남자였나요?
Evelyn, was this the guy?
예, 그사람 이었어요
Yeah. That's him.
전 에반과 여자애들이 집에 없었다는게 기쁘네요
I'm glad Evan and the girls weren't home.
웃긴것은,
Funny thing is,
저 역시도 집에 있으면 안됬었죠
I wasn't supposed to be home either.
그가 우리가 집에 없을거란 것을
미리 알았던 것 같아요
It's almost like he knew we
weren't supposed to be here.
파일들에 특별한 점이 있나요?
Anything special about those files?
그냥 서류들과, 법률 서류들 그리고
Just paperwork, legal documents,
로이의 오래된 사건 노트들이에요
notes on Roy's old cases.
노트북에 관련된 것은요?
무.. 무엇이 있었죠?
What about his computer?
What--what was on that?
그의 오래된 작업 파일들이지만
His old work files, but mostly,
전 레시피라든가 크리스마스 카드에 사용해요
I use it for Christmas cards and recipes.
그들은 귀중품이나 현금이 아닌
They went after Montgomery's files.
몽고메리의 파일에 접근했어요
Not valuables, not cash.
그리고 우리의 도둑님은 죽었고
And now our thief is dead
그가 훔친 파일은 사라졌다고요?
and the files he took are missing?
뭐, 아직 결론으로 넘어가진 말죠
Well, let's not jump to conclusions.
그거에 관해 또 뭐가 있나요?
What else would it be about?
모든사람들은 몽고메리의 죽음이
Everyone here thinks Montgomery died
정의의 경찰 살인범을 들고왔다고 생각해요
bringing a cop killer to justice.
우리가 오직 아는 것은
그가 정말로 어딘가에 관여 했다는 것과
We're the only ones who know
what he was really involved in
그와 당신의 어머니 사건과 연결 되어 있어요
and his connection to your mother's murder.
베켓, 그건 우연일 수 없어요
Beckett, it can't be a coincidence.
다시 피해자의 전과기록을 확인해봐
Recheck the vic's rap sheet.
찾아봐서 만일 몽고메리의
체포기록에 연관이 있으면
See if Montgomery was involved
in any of his old arrests,
그 번호를 가지고 와
and get on that number.
그가 죽기 직전 누구와 이야기 했는지
알고 싶으닌까
I want to know who he was
talking to just before he died.
안심 될만한 뭔갈 말해봐요
Say something reassuring.
뉴욕시에는 매년 수천개의
불법침입 사건이 일어나요
(break-ins:도둑들이 몰래 집에침입 그런것)
There are thousands of break-ins
in New York City every year.
이건 다르게 느껴져요
This one feels different.
그렇다고, 그것은 이것을 의미하지 않아요
Well, that doesn't mean that it is.
몽테고리는 수백개의 사건을 수사했어요
Montgomery worked hundreds of cases.
단지 이 남자가 어떤 파일을 훔쳤다는 이유로
Just because this guy was after files
당신의 어머니 사건이
관련 되어 있다고 할수 없어요
doesn't mean he was after your mom's case.
그렇다면 이 도둑은 왜 죽었나요?
Then why is our thief dead?
당신은 몽고메리와
연관되어 있는 사람을 알고있고,
You know those people that
Montgomery was involved with,
그들이 내가 사건과 다가 갈수록
he said that they wanted me dead,
나를 죽일려하는거라는 것을 알아서
that I was getting too close,
그는 자신의 목숨을 받쳐서라도
and he said that he was gonna give his life
나를 지키려 했었지만
in order to protect mine,
그들은 여전히 절 죽이려 하고 있어요
and they still tried to kill me.
전 가끔씩 일어날때마다 생각하죠
I wake up sometimes, and I think to myself,
어떻게 내가 아직도 살아있는거지? 라고
how the hell am I still alive?
제가 마치 기다리고 있는거 같아요
다른 신발이 떨어질때까지
It's like I'm just waiting
for that other shoe to drop.
이 사건이 그 다른 신발이면 어떻하죠?
What if this is that other shoe?
Castle Season4 Episode 23 (Season Finale)
"Always"
한글자막 by Kay L 오역의역직역이 난무합니다
대충 이해되는 정도의 자막입니다 도저히 뭐라 할지 모르는것은 영어로 남겼습니다 ㅠ
일들이 드디어 그녀와 나를 위해
Things were finally getting better for her,
나아지고 있었어요
for us.
그녀가 막 그녀의 마음을 열었는데
She was just coming out of her shell,
and now this?
넌 정말로 그녀의 엄마 사건과
Do you really think it's related
이 사건이 연관 되었다 생각하니?
to her mother's murder case?
제발 아니길 신께 빌고 있어요
I hope to God it isn't.
몽고메리의 친구들은 깨끗했어요
Montgomery's friend was very clear.
그녀가 다시 사건을 건들인다면
She starts poking around
her mother's murder,
그들은 다시 그녈 찾아가겠죠
they'll come after her again.
전 그렇게 냅둘수 없어요
I can't let that happen.
나도 안단다
I know.
고마워요
Thank you.
잠은 좀 잤어요?
Did you get any sleep?
벌로요
Not much.
우리의 피해자에게 새로운 것은 없어요?
Anything new on our victim?
올랜도의 체포 기록들을 다시 확인 하였지만
We rechecked Orlando's rap sheet.
몽고메리는 모두 연관 되지 않았어요
Montgomery wasn't involved
in any of his old arrests.
그 불법침입은 개인적인게 아니였어요
That break-in wasn't personal.
피해자가 죽지전 그에게 온 전화는요?
What about the call he
made before he was killed?
버너 폰에서 온 전화였어요(일회용전화인듯)
등록된 소유자는 없어요
It's from a burner phone.
There's no registered owner.
-Hey
-Hmm?
Hey.
Hmm?
당신은 혼자가 아니에요
You're not in this alone.
난 여기 있어요
I'm here.
나도 알아요
I know.
Hey
Hey.
그들과 몽고메리와의 충돌에 관해
We may have been wrong
우리가 잘못 생각 했언거 같아요
about why they hit Montgomery's.
목격 자들이 히스패닉 남성이
Maroon DeVille를 타고 골목길을
Witnesses saw a Hispanic
male fleeing the alley
도주하는것을 목격 했어요
in a late-model Maroon DeVille.
분명히 그의 목에는 갱 문신이 있었고
Apparently he had gang ink on his neck--
그것은 사자를 바탕으로 한 "C"
a lion framed by a "C."
카자도르?
Cazador?
피해자와 같이 일을 벌인 갱이에요
The very same gang that
our victim ran with.
Gangs
Gangs.
만약 이 자가 그 골목에 있었다면
If this guy was in that alley,
올랜도를 죽였을 확률이 높아요
odds are, he killed Orlando.
번호판은 얻었어?
Did we get a license plate?
아니요, 하지만 갱 전담반에서 말하길
Uh, no, but according to gang task force,
정차되었던 차량은 Vicente Delgado
의 차와 일치하다고 했어요
the ride matches the car
of one Vicente Delgado.
카자도레스 높은 위치의 보스에요
High-level shot caller for the Cazadores.
그리고 이걸 보세요
And get this.
그의 친척인 Diego Gutierrez는
95년도에 있었던 두 살인사건 용의자로
His cousin Diego Gutierrez
was busted by Montgomery
몽고메리에게 체포되었었어요
for a double homicide in '95.
몽고메리가 사망한지 한달후
His lawyer's filed a motion for retrial
그의 변호사는 재심을 준비했어요
a month after Montgomery was killed.
그를 찾아
Find him.
NYPD! 당장 손이 보이게 해!
NYPD! Let me see your hands right now!
움직이지마!X3
Don't move! Don't move! Don't move!
손이 보이게 올려!
Let me see your hands!
Well, looky here,
9mm이네
a 9 millimeter.
올랜도 코스타스가 맞은 총과 똑같네
Just like the gun that
killed Orlando Costas.
난 이미 말했지
난 골목 길에 없었다고
I already told you, I was
nowhere near that alley.
그뜻은 댁들 목격자는 장님인거야
Fact is, your witnesses are blind.
그 사실은 너는 올랜도를 알고있는거지
The fact is, you knew Orlando Costas.
그래 나는 그가 돌아오기전 한번 보았어
Yeah, I knew him once,
before he turned his back.
그에 관해 마지막으로 본적은요?
When was the last time you heard from him?
-몇년 동안
-몇시간 전이죠
Not in years.
Hours.
그가 죽기 바로 직전
너가 가지고 있던 같은 버너폰으로부터
Just before he was killed,
Orlando called a burner cell,
전화를 받았었어
same phone that we found on you.
그러니 인정하고 자신의 인생에서
30년을 구하는건 어때?
So why don't you just admit to
it and save yourself 30 years?
당신은 그를 로이 몽고 메리 집에
침입하게 한뒤
You had him break in to
Roy Montgomery's house
너의 친척 사건파일을 훔치게 하고는
and steal your cousin's case files,
그를 쏴 죽였지
and then you shot him.
뭘 알아낸거야, 아가씨?
What you got, chica, huh?
총은 분명 맞지 않을거야
Gun's not gonna be a match.
그래서 그 전화기와 그 흔한 자동차를 본
So that leaves you with what, a phone call,
몇몇 사람들 때문에 날 의심하는거야?
and a couple of people who
saw a very common car?
아가씨,당신이 내게 죄를 씌울수 없어,
왠지 알아?
You know why you can't
pin this on me, chica?
난 거기 없었거든
I wasn't there.
The hell you weren't
The hell you weren't.
곧 탄도 검사가 나올 것이야
That's gonna be ballistics.
협상 할수있는 마지막 기회야
Last chance to make a deal.
그를 마약과 무기소지 혐의로 체포해
Book him on the drugs and weapons charge
그리고 나는 검사에게 가서
살인 사건용 파일을 가지고 오지
and tell the D.A. I'm gonna
want to file for murder one.
그가 아니였어요
It wasn't him.
무슨 뜻이야, 그가 아니라는게?
What do you mean, it wasn't him?
아까 레이니가 발견한 피해자의 손톱 밑에
The skin tissue that
Lanie was able to scrape
있었던 피부조직을
from underneath our victim's fingernails,
연구실에서 DNA를 얻어
the lab was able to pull D.N.A.
빈센트와 비교를 해보았지만
We ran it against Vicente.
일치 하지 않았어요
It's not a match.
시스템 안의 모든 사람과도
일치하지 않았어요
In fact, it wasn't a match
to anyone in the system.
그러나, 다른 현장에서 발견한
But it did match D.N.A. trace evidence
DNA와는 일치 했어요
found at another crime scene.
다행히 뭔가 하나라도 있네요
현장은 어떠했어요?
Well, at least that's something.
What was the crime scene?
총격 사건 이였어요
It was a shooting.
베켓, 당신의 사건이요
Beckett, it was your shooting.
이 DNA의 주인공은
D.N.A. confirms that the man
올랜도 코스타스를 골목길에서 죽인자와
who killed Orlando Costas in that alley
당신을 쏜 사람은 같아요
is the same man who put
a bullet in your heart.
11개월동안 연결되지 않았다가 지금 나타났어
No leads for 11 months, and now this.
게이츠 반장님도 알고 계셔?
Does Gates know?
아니요
No.
그렇다면 반장님께 말하지마
Then we don't tell her.
만약 반장님이 이 사실을 알게 된다면
If she finds out this is
a match to my shooting,
날 이 사건에서 빼시겠지
she'll take me off the case.
케이트. 차라리 이 사건에서 빠지는건 어때요
Maybe you should be off this case.
이미 그들은 한번 당신을 죽일려 했어요
They tried to kill you once, Kate.
계속 이렇게 앞으로 나아간다면 그들은....
You keep going on this, they...
그들을 막도록 다시 노력해보면 안될까요?
What's to stop them from trying again?
이제 어떻게 그들을 막아요?
What's to stop them now?
아니요
No.
나는 몇년 동안 기다려 왔어요
I've been waiting a year for this,
그렇기때문에 누군가 이 일을 망친다면
난 미쳐버릴꺼에요
and I'll be damned if I let
someone else screw it up.
이봐, 하비
Hey, Javier.
왠지 잘못 된 기분이 들어
Man, this just feels wrong.
게이츠 반장님께 말해야 할것 같아
We need to tell Gates.
왜....
Why...
그래서 반장님이 베켓을 집에 보내게 할려고?
So she can send Beckett home?
그 방법이 통할 것이라 생각해?
You think that's gonna work?
그렇게 하면 그녀가 멈출 것이라 생각해?
You think that's gonna stop her?
케빈, 그녀는 팀에 있든 없든
She's gonna investigate this case, Kevin,
이 사건을 계속 조사할 것이야
whether she's on it or not.
우리가 적어도 해줄수 있는것은
The least we can do
그녀의 뒤를 맡아 주는거야
is make sure that we have her back.
Hello
Hello.
제생각엔, 캐슬씨는 알것 같군요
제가 왜 전화를 걸었는지
I think you know why I'm
calling, Mr. Castle.
당신이군요
It's you.
Thank God
대체 무슨 일이 일어나는겁니까?
Thank God. What the hell is going on?
왜 그들이 몽고메리 집에 침입한거죠?
Why'd they break in to Montgomery's place?
뭐, 아마도 일을 처리하는 것이겠죠
(clean up은 주로 장소를 정리하는 것)
Well, most likely, it's a clean-up job.
몽고메리의 파일들에 잘못된 것들이 없게
Making sure that Montgomery had
nothing else incriminating
잘 확인 하세요
in his files.
베켓을 사건으로 부터 떨어지게 하세요
As long as Beckett drops her investigation,
우린 아직까지 게임을 조종할 카드를 가지고 있어요
we still hold all the cards.
아니, 그녀는 이미 저격범에게 다가가고 있어요
No, she's already on to her shooter.
그녀는 그냥 놔두질 않을 겁니다
She's not gonna let go.
그렇다면 문제가 생겼군요
Then we have a problem.
만약 그녀가 멈추지 않는다면
그들도 보복 할겁니다
If she doesn't stop, they will retaliate.
만약 당신이 그녀를 컨트롤 할수 없다면
Now I can't control the situation
전 지금 이 상황을 컨트롤 할수 없어요
if you can't control her.
난 당신을 최소 5년간을 감옥에 있게 할만한
I got enough on the drug
and weapons charges
마약 및 무기 소지 혐의를 충분히 가지고 있어요
to put you away for at least five years.
당신의 인생에서 5년...
Five years of your life...
그것의 가치는 뭐죠?
What's that worth?
난 당신이 올랜도를 죽이지 않았다는걸 알아요
I know you didn't kill Orlando.
하지만 그는 당신에게 연락했고
But he called you,
당신과 2분동안 대화를 나눴어요
and you talked to him for two minutes,
그리고 그 골목길에 있었었죠
and you were in that alley.
왜죠?
Why?
이곳엔 나와 당신을 빼고 아무도 없어요
There's nobody in here but you and me.
이곳엔 감시 카메라와
There's no cameras,
마이크는 없어요 그리고,
누군가 들을 사람도 없어요
no microphones, no one's listening.
난 이 혐의들을 없앨수 있어요
I can make all those charges go away.
5년을 다시 가지게 되는거죠
Five years of your life back,
다만, 알고 있는 전부를 말해 줘야해요
but you gotta tell me what you know.
저번주에 그가 전화를 했어
He called last week.
"Times were bad,"라고 말하길레
Talking about "Times were bad,"
"일을 가져다 줄수 있어"라고 대답했어
so I told him, "I can get you some work."
그러나 그는 알고 있었어
만일 그가 카자오레스로 돌아온다면
But he knew if he came
back to the Cazadores,
시간이 없을 거란 것을
there'd be no leaving this time.
그리고 그가 절실히 원했던것은 대출이였고
And all he really wanted was a loan
나는 오래전 일을 위해 그를 도와줄수도 있었지
and could I help him out
for old times' sake.
그에게 그걸 줬나요?
Did you give it to him?
아니, 그가 내게 간청 하더라고
No. He begged me.
그가 그건 자신있게 할수있다고 대답했어
Said he was good for it.
그를 온전하게 해줄 어떤 큰일이
Said he had something big coming up,
찾아올것이라고 말했어
something that'd make him whole.
그 사람이 뭐라 했다고요?
Did he say what?
아니, 그가 오늘 아침 나에게 전화를 했어
No, but that morning, my phone rings,
일이 잘못 되었다고 하더라고
and he said it'd all gone wrong,
그는 절망하면서 그들이 자길 죽일꺼라고 했어
he was desperate, talking about
they were gonna kill him.
그들이 누구지?
Who's they?
몰라
Don't know.
그러나 그는 무서워했지
But he was scared.
왜 너에게 연락한거지?
Why did he call you?
Protection, chica
Protection, chica.
그가 말하길 내가 그를 도와주면
그가 돌아온다고 했어
He said if I helped him
out, he'd come back,
그리고 그는 대가를 알고 있지
and he knew that was the price.
그래서 내가 만나자고 했어
So I told him where to meet.
하지만 내가 갔을때는
그는 이미 죽어 있었어
But by the time I got
there, he was already dead.
네가 어디서 만나자고 말했다고?
You told him where to meet?
맞아
That's right.
-누군가에게 말했나요?
-안했어
You didn't tell anyone else?
No.
거기서 뭔가 봤나요?
Did you see anything there?
백인이고
White guy,
6피트 (182.88cm)
6'.
그가 밤에 삼키기전 얼핏 본거야
Caught a glimpse before the
night swallowed him whole.
그들은 올랜도의 핸드폰을
도청해야 했을거야
They must have been
tapping Orlando's phone.
그것이 그들이 먼저 도착할 방법이닌까
That's the only way they got there first.
하지만 어떻게 그들은 올랜도를 알게되었을까요?
But how did they know to
target Orlando for the job?
그가 돈이 절실했기 때문이지 않을까요
Because he was desperate for money.
알지만, 어떻게 그들이 그것을 알았죠?
Yeah, but how did they know that?
어떻게 그들이 그의 배경을 알게 되었지?
How did they know his background?
왜냐면 그들이 그를 군대에서 알게 되었겠죠
Because they knew him from the military.
그는 자신이 아는 사람에게서 고용됐을 거에요
He was hired by somebody he knew.
그곳이 시작점이네
It's a place to start.
그리고 누구든지 비밀에 가까이 가면 죽었어요
And whoever's gotten close
to that secret is dead.
제생각에 우리들 머리가
이곳에 있어 다행인거 같아요
I think it's clear, we're
in over our heads here.
스스로에게 물어보세요
Speak for yourself, bro.
올랜도의 재정 기록이 왔어요
Orlando's financials just came in.
그의 계정에 만달러가 송금 된뒤
(grand가 천 임으로 10grand면 만인듯)
He was underwater and
overdrawn until last week
그는 지난주까지 수중에 초과 인출을 했어요
when a wire transfer for
10 grand hit his account.
내가 맞혀보지, 추적할수 없다고?
Let me guess. Untraceable?
막다른 곳이네요
So it's a dead end.
예금(보증금?)은 있지만
The deposits are,
계정에서 인출하진 않았어요
but the debit withdrawals are not.
돈이 들어왔을때
Right when the money came in,
마리솔은 청구서를 갚기 위해 썼어요
Marisol started using it to pay bills.
잠깐, 마리솔이 돈에 관해 알고있었다면....
Wait. If Marisol knew about the money...
그렇다면 그녀는 올란도가 뭔가 꾸미고 있다는걸
알고 있었다는 거죠
Then she knew Orlando was up to something.
우리에게 거짓말을 했어
She lied to us.
그것 뿐만이 아니라
Not only that, but according to the bank,
한시간전 그녀는 계정의 모든 돈을 뽑았어요
she cleaned out the entire
account an hour ago.
그녀는 도망치고 있어
She's on the run.
당신이 타운을 벗어 나기전에
몇가지 질문 할게 있어요
I've got a few questions for
you before you leave town,
그리고 이번엔
and this time,
진실만을 이야기 해줘요
I want the truth.
난 지금 진실을 이야기 하고 있어요
I'm telling you the truth.
오늘까지 돈에 관해서
I didn't know anything about the money.
전 아무것도 몰랐어요
Not until today.
그렇다면 왜 우리는 당신의 계정과 반대되는
So why do we have debits against it
인출액이 있는거죠?
the moment it appeared in your account?
-올랜도
-마리솔, 이건 당신 카드에요
Orlando--
It was your card, Marisol.
누가 올랜도를 위해 일을 했었나요?
Who was Orlando working for?
당신이 협조를 안해준다면
Do you know what's gonna happen
어떻게 되는지 아나요?
if you don't cooperate?
당신은 감옥에 가게 될 것이고
You're gonna go to jail
당신의 아이는 시설에 맡겨질거에요
and your kid's gonna go to foster care.
-이게 당신이 원하는 것인가요?
-베켓
Is that what you want?
Beckett--
마르코는 거리에서,10살때
카자도레스에 의해 입대하게되고
Marco on the streets,
enlisted by the Cazadores
그리고 그는 아빠처럼
at age 10 like his father,
19때 배수구에서 죽겠죠!
dead in a gutter at 19!
Pudrete en el infierno!(스페인욕임)
지옥에서 썩어라!
Pudrete en el infierno!
베켓..
이제 그만해요
Beckett...
That's enough.
올랜도가 말하길,
그가 기관에서 알게된사람이 있는데
Orlando said it was someone
he knew from the service,
그 사람은 위험한 사람이라고 했어요
someone dangerous.
그러나 단지 딱 한번이였고
But it was just a one-off,
쉽게 많은 돈을 벌수있는 일이였어요
a lot of money for an easy job.
그리고 우리는 돈이 필요했죠
And we needed the money.
어떤 일이였죠?
What was the job?
그들은 죽은 경찰 집에 있는
They needed files...
파일들을 필요로 했어요....
from a dead cop's house.
어떤 파일들이죠?
What files?
그가 찾을수 있는 모든것들이요
All of them, any he could find,
그 남자 이름을 아나요?
this guy from the service,
did you get a name?
-아니요
-만난 적은 있나요?
No.
Did you meet him?
아니요
No.
그가 집에 전화 건적이 있나요?
Did he ever call the house?
그는 시간과 장소가 적힌 종이를
He left notes for Orlando in the mail box
메일 박스를 통해 올랜드에게 전해줘요
with a time and place.
그들은 코드를 사용하기 때문에
전..전 어딘지 몰라요
They were coded so I-I wouldn't know where.
그러나 단 한번 제가 차에 있었을 때
But I was in the car once.
그들이 어디서 만나는지 봤어요
I saw where they met.
State Street에 위치한
At a church
교회에서요
over on State Street.
수요일이라고 말씀하셨나요?
Wednesday, you say?
네, 오후 3시 쯤이요
Yeah, around 3:00 P.M.
그는 누군가를 만나고 있었어요
He was meeting with someone.
죄송해요 제가 도울수 있었으면 좋겠네요
I'm sorry. I wish I could help.
하지만 우리가 교회를 퍼블릭으로 열기때문에
But we're open to the public,
매일마다 새로운 얼굴들을 봐서 잘 모르겠네요
and we get a lot of
unfamiliar faces every day.
우리는 그들이 기도하게 내비 둡니다
We usually just leave
them to their prayers.
만일 기부 상자가 이렇게 공개적인 장소에 있다면
If your donation box is any indication,
많은사람들이 안을 볼수 있겠는데요
it looks like being open to the
public comes with a price.
네, 그렇죠...
그렇게 좋은 동네는 아니닌까요
Yes, well... it's not
the best neighborhood.
우리는 아웃리치 프로그램을 이용해서
We catch gang kids and the
homeless all the time,
나쁜 애들이나 노숙자를 잡아요
(outreach:(지역 주민에 대한 기관의 적극적인) 봉사 활동)
trying to take advantage of more
than just our outreach programs.
그들을 어떻게 잡나요?
How do you catch them?
이쯤이네요
Here it is,
수요일 오후 3시
3:00 P.M. Wednesday.
올랜도가 왔어요
There's Orlando.
그 놈이에요
That's him.
젠장
Damn it.
제발 제발
Come on. Come on.
Yes
Yes.
저렇게 생긴 놈이였군
So that's what you look like.
전 CID를 통해 알아 볼게요
I'm gonna run this through Army C.I.D.
만일 그들이 군대에서 만났다면
올랜도 부대에 있던 누군가는
If they met in the military
someone in Orlando's old unit
-그 사람의 신원을 알지도 몰라요
-아니, 우리는 누가 연관 되어있는지
might be able to I.D. him.
No, no, we don't know who's involved
얼만큼 멀리 있는지를 몰라
and we don't know how high this goes.
우리가 이 사진을 들고나가서
The minute we put this photo out there,
그와 관련된 사람들이 보게 된다면
그는 사라질려 할테고
these people are gonna know.
He's gonna disappear,
우린 다시는 그를 볼 수 없을 거야
and we'll never see him again.
우리가 알아서 해야 해
We have to do this one on our own.
베켓, 그건 불가능 해요
Beckett, that's impossible.
우리가 그의 얼굴을 안다해서
All we have is a face--
신원을 모른체 그를 찾을 수 없어요
no name, no I.D., no way to find this guy.
그럼 우리가 그를 찾을 방향을 찾아야지
Then we will find a way to find him.
난 이 단서를 놓치지 않을거야
I'm not gonna lose this lead.
우리가 조사 할 수 없는 경우
How are we supposed to investigate
어떻게 조사를 하라는 거지?
if we can't investigate?
그녀의 말을 들었잖아
You heard the lady.
우린 방법을 찾을거야
We find a way.
케이트!
Kate!
지금 죽으면 안돼!
Don't die on me!
널 고용한 사람이 누구지?
Who hired you to kill her?
잊어버려, 넌 절대
그 사람에게 다을 수 없어
Forget it. You'll never touch 'em.
Hey
Hey.
방금 에스파지토에게서 연락 받았어요
I just got off the phone with Esposito.
우리의 킬러는 키채인을 가지고 있었고
Our killer had a keychain,
그것은 Eastway Car Rentals와 일치해요
and he matched it to Eastway Car Rentals.
그것은 수천대 중 하나 일수도 있어요
That could be any one of a thousand cars.
나도 알아요, 이건 건초더미 속의 바늘찾기죠
(사막에서 바늘 찾기와 같은 의미)
I know, it's a needle in a haystack,
그래도 건초더미잖아요
but at least it's a haystack,
그들의 라이센스의 대부분은
파일에 보관되어 있어요
and they keep most of
their licenses on file.
-케이트..
-뭐, 그가 가짜신분증을 사용할수도 있게죠
Kate--
Yeah, he's probably using a fake I.D.
하지만 우리는 범위를 줄여야해요
But we should be able to
narrow it down from there.
-케이트
-무슨 일이에요?
Kate.
What's wrong?
저기, 음...
You, um...
멈춰야 해요
You have to stop.
이 사건, 당신은 멈춰야만 해요
This investigation, you--you have to stop.
캐슬, 우리 이미 이거에 관해 이야기 했잖아요
Castle, we already talked about this.
난 괜찮아요
잘 컨트롤 하고 있어요
I'm fine. I'm in control.
아니요, 그렇지 않아요
No, you're not.
그들이 그렇죠
They are.
케이트, 지금 멈추지 않는다면
그들은 당신을 죽일거에요
And if you don't stop,
they will kill you, Kate.
무슨 소리 하는거에요?
What are you talking about?
몽고메리가 그 격납고에 들어가기 전에
Before Montgomery went into that hangar,
그는 누군가에게 패키지를 보냈어요
he sent a package to someone,
그가 믿는 누군가에게...
someone... he trusted.
그 패키지는 이 일의 배후에게
It contained information
상당한 데미지를 줄수 있는 정보였어요
damaging to the person behind all this.
몽고메리는 당신을 지키기 위해 노력했어요
Montgomery was trying to protect you.
하지만 그 패키지는
당신이 총에 맞을때까지 도착하지 않았어요
But the package didn't arrive
until after you'd been shot.
몽고메리의 친구분은...
Montgomery's friend...
그들과 협상을 했어요
struck a deal with them.
만일 그들이 당신을 냅둔다면
If they left you alone,
그 패키지 안의 정보들은
that package and the information inside
절대 세상 밖으로 나오지 않는 다는 이야기였죠
would never see the light of day.
그러나 그들은 한가지 조건을 제시했고
당신은 한발 물러섰죠
But they made one condition--
you had to back off.
그리고 케이트, 당신이 살아남은 이유가 있어요
And that's the reason you're alive, Kate,
이유는 당신이 멈췄기 때문이죠
because you stopped.
어떻게 알고 있는 거죠?
How do you know this?
일을 진행시키기 위해서는
In order for the deal to work,
누군가는 당신이 밀고나가지 않게
잡아야만 했어요
someone had to make sure
you weren't pursuing it.
당신도 관여 되어 있나요?
Are you a part of this?
전 단지 당신이 안전하길 바랬어요
I was just trying to keep you safe.
제 인생에 있어 가장 중요한 일인데
By lying to me
제게 거짓말을 해요?
about the most important thing in my life?
당신을 보호할 방법은
거짓말 밖에 없었어요
That lie was the only thing
that was protecting you.
캐슬, 전 보호따위 필요없어요
Castle, I didn't need protection.
나는 단서가 필요했고
I needed a lead,
당신은 1년간 그 단서위에 있었어요
and you sat on it for a year.
그 사람이 누구죠?
제가 어떻게 그사람을 찾을수 있죠?
Now who is this person? How do I find him?
그는 통화로만 말했어요
He's a-a voice on the phone.
그는 주차장 그림자로만 보여줬어요
He's a shadow in a parking garage.
그 사람을 만났었어요?
You met with him?
당신은 그 사람이 이 사건의
배후가 아닌것을 어떻게 알죠?
How do you know that he's
not behind my mom's murder?
그가 연관 되어있지 않다는것을
어떻게 알죠?
How do you know that he's not involved?
그리고 어떻게 이렇게 할수가 있는거죠?
And how the hell could you do this?
왜냐하면 전 당신을 사랑하니까요
Because I love you.
하지만 당신은 이미 알고 있었죠
안그런가요?
But you already know that, don't you?
1년간 알고 있었잖아요
You've known for about a year.
지금 장난해요?
Are you kidding me?
당신은 사실 나에게 이 일을 꺼내서
You're actually bringing this up right now,
나에게 말을 해준뒤
날 배신할려했나요?
after you told me that
you just betrayed me?
케이트, 내말좀 들어봐요
Kate, listen to me--
말을 들어보라고요?
내가 왜 당신 말을 들어야 하는거죠?
Listen to you? Why should I listen to you?
어떻게 내가 당신이 말하는 모든 것을
믿을 수 있죠?
How I am even supposed to
trust anything that you say?
어떻게 그...
How are you s--
왜냐하면 모든 힘든 일들을 우린 함께 겪었어요!
Because of everything we've
been through together!
4년동안 난 여기 서 있었어요
Four years, I've been right here.
계속 나는 기다렸어요
당신이 내가 여기 있다는 것을
Four years just waiting for
you to just open your eyes,
알아 줄때까지
to see that I'm right here
그리고 나는 단순한 파트너가 아니란 것을요
and that I'm more than a partner.
난 단지 당신의 웃는 얼굴을 보기 위해
Every morning, I-I bring
you a cup of coffee
매일 아침 커피를 가져 다 줘요
just so I could see a smile on your face
왜냐하면, 당신은
제가 만나 본 사람들 중 가장..
because I think you are the most...
remarkable...
놀라우며
maddening...
화가 나는...
challenging...
도전적이고..
나를 좌절하게 만드는 사람이죠
frustrating person I have ever met.
그리고 케이트, 난 당신을 사랑해요, 만약...
And I love you, Kate, and if...
이 말이 당신에게 의미가 있다면,
that means anything to you,
당신이 날 생각해 준다면
이러지 말아요
if you care about me at
all, just don't do this.
만일 내가 당신을 염려한다면요?
If I care about you?
캐슬, 당신은 내 인생을 가지고 거래를 했어요
Castle, you cut a deal for my life
마치 내가 (구별 못하는)어린 아이 인것처럼
like I was some kind of a child.
내 인생이에요...
My life, mine...
당신이 결정할 필요 없어요
You don't get to decide.
당신이 계속 이렇게 나아간다면
You keep going with this,
그들이 결정할꺼에요
they're gonna decide.
케이트, 그들은 당신을 찾아올 거에요
They're gonna come for you, Kate.
오게 냅둬요
Let them come.
그들은 Coonan을 보냈었고
그는 죽었어요
They sent Coonan, and he is dead.
그들이 Lockwood를 보냈으나 죽었어요
They sent Lockwood, and he is dead.
그리고 난 아직 여기있어요 캐슬
And I am still here, Castle,
그리고 난 준비 되었어요
and I am ready.
무엇이 준비되었는데요
Ready for what,
죽..죽을 준비가 된거요?
to-to die for your cause?
케이트 이건 단순한
살인 사건이 아니에요
This isn't a murder
investigation anymore, Kate.
그들은 전쟁으로 돌리고 있어요
They've turned it into a war.
만약 그들이 전쟁을 원한다면
If they want a war, then
I will bring them a war,
내가 그들 앞으로 전쟁을 가져다 줄거에요
straight to their doorsteps.
이제 더이상 내가 할말은 없는것 같군요
그렇죠?
Well, I guess there's just
nothing I can say, is there?
그렇다면, 음...
Okay, um...
맞아요, 케이트 당신이 옳아요
Yeah, you're right, Kate,
이건 당신의 인생이죠
it's your life.
당신이 원한다면 멀리 던져버릴수 있죠
You can throw it away if you want,
그러나 난 더이상
당신 을 지켜보지도 곁에 있지도 않을거에요
but I'm not gonna stick
around and watch you,
그렇다면 이제...
so this is, uh...
끝이에요
over.
이만 갈게요
I'm done.
괜찮아요?
Everything okay?
그래 괜찮아, 너의 연설문은 어떻게 되가니?
Yeah. Fine. How's your speech coming?
지금까지 쓴 모든 졸업 연설문을 계속
I have watched or read
보거나 읽고 있고요
every graduation address ever written
가장 좋은 것들을 하나씩 충고해가면서
편집한뒤
and compiled all the best
advice into one speech,
그러고 나서 큰 소리로 읽어봐요
and then I read it out loud.
그리고 맞춰봐요 제가 어떤 소리를 냈는지
And guess what I sounded like.
pompous ass같은 소리를 냈어요
Like a pompous ass.
난 18살이에요
내가 대체 뭘 알겠어요?
I'm 18 years old. What the hell do I know?
애야 보렴, 너가 아는것들,
Hey, look, everything you know,
너가 알게된 모든것들은
everything you will know is...
너를 위한 진실들이란다
is what's true for you.
내가 아는것은, 모든것은 변한다는거야
All I know is, everything's changing.
모든것들은 다른 방향으로 가고 있어요
Everything's going to be different,
그리고 나는 그게 두려워요
and I'm so scared.
뭐가 말이니?
Of what?
앞으로 나아가는거요
Moving on.
그걸 관해 쓰렴
Write about that.
너의 진실 된 감정들을
That feels true.
캐슬은 어딨어요?
Where's Castle?
그는 팀에서 나갔어
He's off the team.
그래서 뭐 찾은거 있어?
So what do we got?
Eastway rented 700 cars last Wednesday.
저희는 용의자 이름이
We believe our suspect
is going under the name
Cole Maddox라고 믿고 있어요
Cole Maddox.
He rented out of J.F.K.
캔자스 운전 면허증을 소지 하고 있어요
It's a Kansas driver's license.
계속 파보니 그것은 위장 신분증이였어요
Now we did some digging.
It's a cover I.D.
자동차는 반환 했어?
Did he return the car?
아뇨, 그러나..
No, but...
이스트웨이에서 GPS장치를
Eastway maintains
관리하고 있어서 저희가 추적해서
GPS tracking on all of its equipment,
반경 1블락 Lower East Side
so we tracked it to the Lower East Side
근처인것을 알아 냈어요
to a 1-block radius somewhere along here.
알았어, 계속 확인하고 있어
All right, you stay on grid.
만약 그가 움직였으면 알려주고
Let us know if he moves.
에스파지토는 날 따라와
Esposito, you're coming with me.
뭐하는거에요?
What are you doing?
당신이 이 일을 하고 싶다면
옳은 방향으로 하세요
You want to do this, you do it right.
당신은 팀을 차에두고
지원팀과 같이 가세요
You put a team on that car and
you bring backup with you.
라이언, 이 모들일이 시작 된 것은
Ryan, this whole thing started
부패 경찰들 때문이야
because of a group of corrupt cops.
너가 밖에 더 이상 없을꺼란걸 어떻게 알지?
How do you know there
aren't more out there?
이 놈을 잡기 몇 인치 전인데, 다른사람에게
We're about an inch away
from catching this guy,
우리의 다음 행동을 알리게 되어서
이 기회를 날려버리고 싶지 않아
and I'm not gonna blow it by
advertising our next move.
맞는 말이지만,
With all due respect,
이 놈은 당신의 심장에 총을 쏘았고
this guy put a bullet in your heart
그리고 공중으로 사라졌어요
and then he disappeared into the ether.
당신은 준비 없이 그곳에 갈수 없어요
You cannot go in there unprepared.
준비 없이?
Unprepared?
난 지난 13년간 준비되어 있었어
I've been preparing for
this for the past 13 years.
이봐, 하비...
Hey, Javier...
이봐, 그녀가 이렇게 하면 안되
Man, don't let her do this.
이건 너무 위험해
It's too big of a risk.
모두다 괜찮아
It's all good, bro.
우린 할 수 있어
We got this.
빨리요, 알렉시스의 연설문이나
Come on. We don't want
to miss her speech...
혹은 졸업식 전체를 놓치고 싶지 않아요
or the entire graduation.
거의 준비 다 되었단다
I'm almost ready.
그를 찾았어요
Hey, we got him.
호텔의 도어맨이 차량 ID를 확인 해줬어요
The doorman at the residency hotel
across the way I.D.'ed the car.
그리고 프러트 직원 말로는
And the front desk clerk confirms
매독스란 사람이 한달간 임대하였다고 해요
that Mr. Maddox is here on a 1-month lease.
그들이 그의 방을 들어가는걸 허락해줬어요
They've agreed to let us in his room.
여기서 나가요
Get out of the way.
Clear
Clear.
몽고메리의 파일들이에요
Montgomery's files.
그의 연락처들?
His contact list?
도대체 뭘 찾고 있던거죠?
What the hell were they looking for?
무언가가 아니야,
누군가야
Not what. Who.
그들은 몽고메리의 웨딩 앨범을 가지고 있어
They grabbed Montgomery's wedding album.
-왜죠?
-그들은 그가 알만한사람을 찾고있어
Why?
They're looking for someone that he knew.
아마 그들은 찾았을 수도 있어요
Maybe they found him.
여기서 나가야해
We gotta get out of here.
난 지원을 부를게
I'm gonna call for backup.
로비에서 준비하고있을.....
으악!
We'll set up in the lobby--
배후가 누군지 그냥 말해줘요
Just tell me who's behind this.
형사, 당신은 시간을 낭비하고 있어
You're wasting your time, detective.
넌 모르지 너가 얼마나 불리한지
You have no idea what you're up against.
너도 마찬 가지야
Neither do you.
사실은...
Actually...
우리는 정확히 누가 불리한 상황인지
알고있지
We know exactly who we're up against.
살려줘요!
Help!
오! 오 신이시여
Oh! Oh, God.
안뒈에!
No!
이렇게는 안돼, 제발
Oh, not like this. Come on.
제발, 쫌!!
Come on. No!
캐슬
Castle.
베켓!
Beckett!
캐슬!
Castle!
-베켓!
-캐슬, 여기에요!
Beckett! Castle, I'm here!
안돼, 꺄!
No!
오, 제발, 캐슬!
Oh, God. Castle!
베켓, 기다려요!
Beckett, hang on!
캐슬!
Castle!
베켓!
Beckett!
캐슬?
Castle?
증거를 감추고
Withholding evidence,
상관을 속이고...
lying to a superior officer--
자네가 한 짓은 시를 망신시키고
뱃지에게 불명예를 안겼어
What you did dishonors this
city and dishonors the badge.
사건에서 손을 때는 것 뿐만 아니라
Not only are you off this investigation,
지금 즉시 나는 두사람에게
I'm putting you both on
administrative leave
-휴직을 내리겠어
-Sir
effective immediately.
Sir--
Don't you "Sir" me.
너희들은 유니폼을 입을 수 있는 자격이 없어
You don't deserve to wear the uniform.
이제 뱃지와 총을 내려놔
Now hand over your badges and guns.
베켓 형사
Detective Beckett.
보관하세요
Keep it.
전 관둘겁니다
I resign.
There's a universal truth
우리 모두가 직면해야 할
we all have to face...
보편적인 진실이 있습니다....
whether we want to or not
우리들이 원하든지 원하지 않던지
whether we want to or not.
Everything eventually ends
모든것은 결국 끝납니다
Everything eventually ends.
As much as I've looked forward to this day,
이 날이 오기 전까지
I've always disliked endings...
전 끝이라는 것을 싫어했습니다
The last day of summer...
여름의 마지막 날
The final chapter of a great book...
위대한 책의 마지막 챕터에서...
Parting ways with a close friend
가까운 친구들과 이별하는 방법
Parting ways with a close friend.
But endings are inevitable
그러나 마지막을 피할 수 없습니다
But endings are inevitable.
하비
Javi.
난 해야만 했어
I had to.
Leaves fall
이파리들은 떨어지고
Leaves fall.
You close the book
당신은 책을 덮고
You close the book.
You say good-bye
작별인사를 합니다
You say good-bye.
Today is one of those days for us
오늘은 우리에게 그런 날 입니다
Today is one of those days for us.
Today we say good-bye to everything that was familiar,
오늘 우리는 친숙하고 편안했던 모든것들에
Today we say good-bye to
everything that was familiar,
everything that was comfortable
작별인사를 전합니다
everything that was comfortable.
We're moving on
우리는 앞으로 나아갑니다
We're moving on.
But just because we're leaving,
그러나 단지 우리가 떠나는것 때문에
and that hurts...
아파옵니다
There are some people
우리 일부분의
who are so much a part of us
몇몇 사람들은
they'll be with us no matter what
무슨 일이 있던지 우리와 함께하게될겁니다
they'll be with us no matter what.
They are our solid ground...
그들은 우리의 굳은 땅이고...
Our North Star
우리의 북쪽 별이며
Our North Star,
and the small clear voices in our hearts
우리의 마음속에 있는 작은 목소리 입니다
that will be with us... always.
그것들은 항상 우리와 함께합니다.. 언제나..
아니야 알렉시스
난 괜찮아
No, Alexis, I'll be fine.
나에겐 몇천개의 채널을 가진
케이블과 Xbox가 있어
I got a thousand cable
channels, I got my Xbox.
즐겁게 보내렴
You have fun.
내일 점심시간 전까지
네 걱정 하지 않을 꺼야
I will not worry about you
until lunchtime tomorrow.
나도 사랑한단다
I love you, too.
베켓, 뭘 원하는 거죠?
Beckett, what do you want?
당신이요
You.
미안해요 캐슬
I'm so sorry, Castle.
정말 미안해요
I'm so sorry.
정말 정말 미안해요
무슨 일이에요?
What happened?
그가 도망쳤지만 전 상관하지 않았어요
He got away, and I didn't care.
내가 거의 죽을 뻔 했을 때
I almost died
당신 생각이 났어요
and all I could think about was you.
I just want you
I just want you.
미스터...
Mister...
스미스?
Smith?
누구요?
Who are you?
당신은 정말 찾기 힘든 사람이군요
You've been a very hard man to find.
원하는게 뭐요?
What do you want?
당신은 나의 고용주들의 중요한
You have some sensitive information
정보들을 알고 있고
about my employer,
그 정보들을 베켓 형사를 보호하기 위해
information that you've been using
사용 하고 있더군요
to protect detective Beckett.
우리의 딜을...
Are you forgetting...
잊은 거요?
we have a deal?
아니요
그것은 협박이였습니다
No. What you had was blackmail.
그럼 지금부터 그 정보들에 관해
Now you're gonna tell me where
all that information is,
어디있는가 말해줘야겠습니다 그후
and after you do,
전 케이트 베켓을땅속에
I'm gonna put Kate Beckett in the ground
다시한번 파묻을 겁니다
once and for all.